The record schedule meeting is a milestone for Monday, July 3, 2023.
That's the gift.
Let's get the personal experiences.
We have none.
Three claims.
Much to a proof.
Yes?
He said, hi.
Hi.
Or, for his minutes, at the June 20th, 2023,
regular meeting.
Motion.
Second.
He said, hi.
Hi.
In the five, same engagement letter from Crawford and Associates.
Motion.
Second.
Six.
If I say manager signature on travelers, authorization
to bind coverage for the fiscal year 23, 24.
CabEx actually ended with travelers during the 30th.
And so in order to keep us moving forward, our city manager had to sign the authorization to bind the coverage.
and so what this is for is just to recognize his signature.
I don't know if you've had time to look at the BR, the air not, but the total premium of all lines of business will be $810,000, $2,076 a year and the approved budget amount was 877 so it came in a little bit less than what we thought it was going to be.
They did send out for bits, for other insurance agencies, or companies for me, just, no, that information is not in here.
We gave us part of the results and we just, because of the year that we've had, they just really couldn't get, we had $1.9 million worth of claims this year, so this really wasn't the best year to try to get someone else to write our coverage.
We've, they've, travelers has paid $348,000 and then they have a $1.6 million pending in claims.
But they did open up for bits.
They did open up for bits.
They got, and they, really, the only person that they got to, to bid on part of was OMAG.
And they wouldn't write all of the lines.
They wouldn't only do part of it.
So if we would have went with OMAG and then the other lines that we would have had to go with separate, it would have cost us $891,000.
So this is a calendar that is our broker today who went out and looked at other coverage to see if there was better through travelers or someone else.
And then there's a few of them that they do break out.
And that's why they go ahead and quote, OMAG and some others.
But they put together what they believe were the best rates we could get.
And considering the losses we had this late in the fiscal year, that's probably part of the reason why some of the rate was coming back this late,
knowing that we were going to run out of time.
But we had big claims that were.
depending. And so they had to make sure they understood what all of those losses were going to be.
And when they basically addressed with the underwriters to get us a new quote.
So we kind of came in just under the wire to get the new quote to get it reviewed and then approved.
So that's why it's got a few fires.
Yeah, hopefully.
You know, there's just, you know, a huge losses.
So.
So we just, we had a 308 percent loss ratio this year.
So when you're, if you're a business, if you're an underwriters, you use a how much of my
bringing in and plenty and premium, how much of my paid out claims.
Yeah, they had a 338 percent loss on us this year.
You know, over the last five years, we're committed about 101 percent loss ratio.
So we're kind of, they're kind of breaking even on us.
So glad they're hanging in there with us.
So is there any needs to do a direct deeper dive on what some of these issues are?
I mean, obviously, we know what started the fires.
I mean, we've got a lot of bomb in the past looking at the trend.
It feels like maybe corrective actions need to be taken.
So what we've actually done is is they have some things they're going to be working with us on that.
Gowder has some programs as well as travelers that we're going to be taking advantage of to see if what we can be doing to mitigate our risk.
And that may be personal training safety training, things like that, but we agree that we need to be doing everything we can to make sure that we're not.
Getting to this loss ratio because we need to have better numbers than this.
It's expensive to have a bad loss ratio right here.
Your rates are going to go on.
So yeah, we've talked about and worked with them and they had lots of great programs that they're going to make it available to us at no cost.
It's just obviously what they do.
So we've committed, in fact, I had a conversation with Chris about it today and leaving on him as well.
Just him in Travis and Kevin to start seeing how we roll this out.
A city wide and then kind of doing a deeper dive and making sure that we're protecting our assets and protecting our people.
So this thing we have tonight we really don't have a choice.
Nope.
You're ratifying the signature that we've already put in Mark here.
Get it with all this.
You have a great work on relationship these guys.
You're good.
Yep.
We have a party.
We will be having a party.
Oh thanks.
You just bullet.
Yeah, the 14th will be his last day.
If we don't okay, since boy already signed it, he paid for it.
Much to approve.
Second.
He's dead.
Five.
Thanks, Jimmy.
Seven.
Did any new business to the riddles of the posting this agenda?
Eight.
Mayor Council, committee announcements?
For the July tomorrow, everybody be safe.
Have fun.
Make sure this isn't the last time you see all your 10 fingers.
All right.
So I'll go a little bit further on that.
For the July, I think we'll be serving some hot dogs and water.
Stuff like that out there.
Yep.
So if you want to come help hand that stuff out.
I don't have access to the same amenities that had latch to your company.
Maybe I can pull some strings.
Hopefully.
Buffalo and we're done.
We'll be out there.
It's going to be lots of great family fun activities.
We're going to have fans.
I think we, this is in collaboration with Peoria Tribe.
City provides fireworks and three hot logs.
Peoria is providing everything else.
Yeah.
Amazing job.
Great work.
Yeah.
I'd say the last three years I wasn't well with this.
It's been a much better event than it was any year in that part.
Just for this year.
Yeah.
And you hear a lot of people say, I don't go.
It's just a buffalo ranch.
It's 16.
You don't have to go inside.
There are things outside.
If you don't feel like going inside, you don't have to.
No.
So the tribe there does a lot to put into this from their own pockets.
Right.
There.
Chief Harper likes us all the day.
And he goes all out for the kids stuff.
He does a concert.
And he uses us on top of fly over.
Yep.
They go all out.
We appreciate their partnership on this for sure.
Food trucks.
Yeah.
It's going to be going to be great.
So the other thing I have is, I went to the Coleman this afternoon.
The quappal tribe had a movie they showed called Imagineing the Indian.
Wow.
That's what a great educational piece.
It was basically about schools and colleges and high schools that use for their mascots.
You know, the Indians or red skins and how offensive it is to try our tribal partners.
And very educational for me, especially.
But if you guys get a chance to see it, it takes about an hour and a half.
I think it's what the movie was.
But well, it was good.
It was good.
And I think they're going to have another showing in Tulsa.
But it'll be public to where you can log on to get some wrong internet.
I'm not sure where.
But it was good piece.
Yeah.
You know.
So you may enter communication.
So the transportation.
As of this time, it's going to remain closed until further notice.
It is closed to the public to the population.
We just don't know when we're going to be able to open it up for safety.
We're still working with the insurance and the fire suppression company.
Try to figure out what we were wrong.
But we have to make sure that.
It's a safe building before we allow the public to go back into it.
And so we've kind of lived a long year,
say it'll be next week, or it'll be next week.
At this point, we still can get to a clarification
of what's wrong with the system.
So rather than just keep living along,
it's close until we can make sure it's safe.
OK, so I would like to ask then that we
think of some alternatives for our systems.
And so we've been talking about what they would look like.
And so we've pulled together some ideas around either putting
roll-offs, or they're accessible, but can be monitored.
Maybe we have a yard waste disposal day,
we can monitor it because, again, we
would just open it up and let people bring the yard waste in there,
but it gets difficult when they bring it up trash.
Right.
Because then obviously it's problem.
So it'll have to be something that we can finally monitor.
But we'll figure out some options.
Because we agree we're going to have to do something.
Lots of citizens that are getting frustrated
because the conversations are having
with code enforcement, the code enforcement, as well,
where in is working with people, very, very forgiving
of what they're timing is going to be.
So they know, and they're working with it.
So we'll welcome up some solutions to bring it back.
The other thing I wanted to bring up,
if I can, in my ear, is our dollar-part and imagination library
that the program the library's going to do in there,
up to 600 kids, and it's a lot of stuff.
Great number there.
And then Kimby hits it out an email.
Do you all regarding me, cracking crab,
2020-3, that's coming up, that'll be August 24th.
So check your calendars.
We'll see if that's something that you adore
your spouses can attend, and I'll get us signed up
for the table because it's always good for us to be there
and support all of our local businesses when we can.
But obviously you have to pay for a table,
and it's part of our support.
So let me know what your availability is.
We'll get, Kimby will get us signed up if you can make it.
Come again, adjournment.
Motion.
Second.
Zero vote.
Hi.
He said.
Holy cow.
15 minutes.
That's the fastest.
That's a regular reason.